<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Math Summaries</title>
    <link>https://quantophile.github.io/mathsummaries/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Math Summaries</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 17:32:54 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://quantophile.github.io/mathsummaries/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Solution of systems of linear equations</title>
      <link>https://quantophile.github.io/mathsummaries/posts/solution_of_systems_of_linear_equations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Mar 2022 17:32:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quantophile.github.io/mathsummaries/posts/solution_of_systems_of_linear_equations/</guid>
      <description>Previously, we consider the solution of a single equation of the form $f(x) = 0$, where $f$ is a real-valued function defined and continuous on a closed interval of the real line. The simplest example of this kind is the linear equation $ax = b$, where $a$ and $b$ are given real numbers, with $a \neq 0$, whose solution is
$$x = a^{-1}b$$
trivially. Of course, we could have expressd the solution as $x = b/a$ as in the previous post, but as we will see in a moment, writing $x = a^{-1}b$ is much more revealing in the present context.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Solution of equations by iteration</title>
      <link>https://quantophile.github.io/mathsummaries/posts/solution_of_equations_by_iteration/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 19:23:36 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quantophile.github.io/mathsummaries/posts/solution_of_equations_by_iteration/</guid>
      <description>Introduction. Equations of various kinds arise in physical applications and a substantial body of mathematical research is devoted to their study. Some equations are rather simple. In our high school days, we all encountered the single linear equation $ax + b = 0$, where $a$ and $b$ are real numbers and $a \neq 0$, whose solution is given by $x = -b/a$. Many equations are however non-linear: a simple example is $ax^2 + bx + c = 0$, $a \neq 0$, involving a quadratic polynomial with real coefficients $a,b,c$ and $a \neq 0$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Null Sets</title>
      <link>https://quantophile.github.io/mathsummaries/posts/null_sets/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Mar 2022 19:24:24 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quantophile.github.io/mathsummaries/posts/null_sets/</guid>
      <description>The idea of a &amp;lsquo;negligible&amp;rsquo; set relates to one of the limitations of the Riemann integral, as we saw in the previous chapter. Since the function $f = \mathbf{1}_\mathbf{Q}$ takes a non-zero value only on $\mathbf{Q}$ and equals $1$ there, the area under it&amp;rsquo;s graph (if such makes sense) must be very closely linked to the length of the set $\mathbf{Q}$. This is why it turns out we cannot integrate $f$ in the Riemann sense: the sets $\mathbf{Q}$ and $\mathbf{R}\setminus \mathbf{Q}$ are so different from intervals that it is not clear how we should measure their lengths and it is clear that the integral of $f$ over $[0,1]$ should equal the length of the set of rationals in $[0,1]$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basic Notions of Probability</title>
      <link>https://quantophile.github.io/mathsummaries/posts/basic_notions_of_probability/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 21:22:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quantophile.github.io/mathsummaries/posts/basic_notions_of_probability/</guid>
      <description>In this post, we review the basic notions of probability that will be needed to study Stochastic Calculus.
Probability Space. Probability theory provides a framework to study random experiments, that is, experiments where the exact outcome cannot be predicted accurately. Such random experiments involve a source of randomness. Elementary random experiments include the roll of the die and consecutive coin tosses. In applications, the source of randomness could be, for example, all the transactions that take place at the New York Stock Exchange in a given time, the times of decay of radioactive material, and pseudorandom numbers generated by a computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joint Distributions</title>
      <link>https://quantophile.github.io/mathsummaries/posts/joint_distributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 21:22:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quantophile.github.io/mathsummaries/posts/joint_distributions/</guid>
      <description>The individual distributions of two random variables do not tell us anything about whether the random varaibles are independent or dependent. Although, the PMF of $X$ is a complete blueprint for the distribution of $X$ and the PMF of $Y$ is a complete blueprint for the distribution of $Y$, these individual PMFs are missing important information about the dependence structure of $X$ and $Y$.
Of course, in real life, we usually care about the relationship between multiple random variables in the same experiment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Binomial Model</title>
      <link>https://quantophile.github.io/mathsummaries/posts/schreve_voli_01_the_binomial_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 13:01:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quantophile.github.io/mathsummaries/posts/schreve_voli_01_the_binomial_model/</guid>
      <description>One-Period Binomial Model. We start with the one-period version of the model. In the further sections, we will easily extend the model to an arbitrary number of periods.
Model description. Running time is denoted by the letter $t$, and by definition we have two points in time $t = 0$ (&amp;ldquo;today&amp;rdquo;) and $t=1$ (&amp;ldquo;tomorrow&amp;rdquo;). In the model, we have two assets: a bond and a stock. At time $t$, the price of the bond is denoted by $B_t$ and the price of one share of the stock is denote by $S_t$.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sequences and Series of Functions</title>
      <link>https://quantophile.github.io/mathsummaries/posts/sequences_and_series_of_functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 20:38:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quantophile.github.io/mathsummaries/posts/sequences_and_series_of_functions/</guid>
      <description>In 1689, Jakob Bernoulli published his Tractus de seriebus infinitis summarizing what was known about the infinite series towards the end of the 17th century. Full of clever calculations and conclusions, this publication was also notable for one particular question that it didn&amp;rsquo;t answer; namely, what is the precise value of the series
$$\sum_{n=1}^{\infty}\frac{1}{n^2} = 1 + \frac{1}{4} + \frac{1}{9} + \frac{1}{16} + \ldots$$
Bernoulli convincingly argued that $\sum \frac{1}{n^2}$ converged to something less than $2$, but he was unable to find an explicit expression for the limit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
