<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>probability on Math Summaries</title>
    <link>https://quantophile.github.io/mathsummaries/tags/probability/</link>
    <description>Recent content in probability on Math Summaries</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 21:22:12 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://quantophile.github.io/mathsummaries/tags/probability/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Basic Notions of Probability</title>
      <link>https://quantophile.github.io/mathsummaries/posts/basic_notions_of_probability/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 21:22:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quantophile.github.io/mathsummaries/posts/basic_notions_of_probability/</guid>
      <description>In this post, we review the basic notions of probability that will be needed to study Stochastic Calculus.
Probability Space. Probability theory provides a framework to study random experiments, that is, experiments where the exact outcome cannot be predicted accurately. Such random experiments involve a source of randomness. Elementary random experiments include the roll of the die and consecutive coin tosses. In applications, the source of randomness could be, for example, all the transactions that take place at the New York Stock Exchange in a given time, the times of decay of radioactive material, and pseudorandom numbers generated by a computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Joint Distributions</title>
      <link>https://quantophile.github.io/mathsummaries/posts/joint_distributions/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 11:36:50 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quantophile.github.io/mathsummaries/posts/joint_distributions/</guid>
      <description>The individual distributions of two random variables do not tell us anything about whether the random varaibles are independent or dependent. Although, the PMF of $X$ is a complete blueprint for the distribution of $X$ and the PMF of $Y$ is a complete blueprint for the distribution of $Y$, these individual PMFs are missing important information about the dependence structure of $X$ and $Y$.
Of course, in real life, we usually care about the relationship between multiple random variables in the same experiment.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
