<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Math Summaries</title>
    <link>https://quantophile.github.io/mathsummaries/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Math Summaries</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 21:22:12 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://quantophile.github.io/mathsummaries/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Basic_notions_of_probability</title>
      <link>https://quantophile.github.io/mathsummaries/posts/basic_notions_of_probability/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Feb 2022 21:22:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quantophile.github.io/mathsummaries/posts/basic_notions_of_probability/</guid>
      <description>In this post, we review the basic notions of probability that will be needed to study Stochastic Calculus.
Probability Space. Probability theory provides a framework to study random experiments, that is, experiments where the exact outcome cannot be predicted accurately. Such random experiments involve a source of randomness. Elementary random experiments include the roll of the die and consecutive coin tosses. In applications, the source of randomness could be, for example, all the transactions that take place at the New York Stock Exchange in a given time, the times of decay of radioactive material, and pseudorandom numbers generated by a computer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Binomial Model</title>
      <link>https://quantophile.github.io/mathsummaries/posts/schreve_voli_01_the_binomial_model/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jan 2022 13:01:03 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quantophile.github.io/mathsummaries/posts/schreve_voli_01_the_binomial_model/</guid>
      <description>Model Description. Running time is denoted by the letter $t$, and by definition we have two points in time, $t=0$ and $t=1$. In the model, we have two assets: a bond and a stock. At time $t$, the bond is denoted by $B_t$ and the price of one share of stock is denoted by $S_t$. Thus, we have two price processes $B$ and $S$.
The bond price process is deterministic and given by,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sequences and Series of Functions</title>
      <link>https://quantophile.github.io/mathsummaries/posts/sequences_and_series_of_functions/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jan 2022 20:38:23 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://quantophile.github.io/mathsummaries/posts/sequences_and_series_of_functions/</guid>
      <description>In 1689, Jakob Bernoulli published his Tractus de seriebus infinitis summarizing what was known about the infinite series towards the end of the 17th century. Full of clever calculations and conclusions, this publication was also notable for one particular question that it didn&amp;rsquo;t answer; namely, what is the precise value of the series
$$\sum_{n=1}^{\infty}\frac{1}{n^2} = 1 + \frac{1}{4} + \frac{1}{9} + \frac{1}{16} + \ldots$$
Bernoulli convincingly argued that $\sum \frac{1}{n^2}$ converged to something less than $2$, but he was unable to find an explicit expression for the limit.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
